Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical]

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Bhavani Prasad Kondari (1) Featured

Relevant 3 years of experience in service now



Current Designation: Servicenow Developer

Current Company: HCL Technolgies

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: ServiceNow, CMDB, Servicenow Developer

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Having total 4.0 years of IT Experience and 3.0 years of relevant experience as a Service Now Developer & Administrator Good Knowledge about IT Infrastructure Library(ITIL) standards, which are helpful in development and customization of IT Service management applications.

Working Experience on Integrations using SOAP and REST.

Involved in different version upgradations of multiple ServiceNow instances.

ServiceNow expert on Incident/Problem Management, Change and Release Management, Reports and Knowledge

Involved in managing system configurations, gathering user/process requirements, developing workflow customizations and managing third party integration for ServiceNow Platform.

Work Experience

HCL Technolgies as Servicenow Developer Oct 2016 to Till Date

ProjectDetails:

Project #1: NVIDIA Corporation Duration: May2018 to oct 2020Tools: ServiceNow

Roles and Responsibilities:

Performing day to day administration of the ITSM, including making approved changesto process/work flows, monitoring MID Servers in ServiceNow tool.

Handling Incidents (including priority incidents - P1 and P2), Service Requests, Change Requests and Adhoc Requests efficiently.

Involved in monitoring and handling third party integrations issues with ServiceNow.

Configuration and customization of ITSM application and other application using Business Rules, Client Script, UI Policies,

UI Actions, Access Control Lists, Dictionary Overrides, and Scheduled Jobs based on client requirement.

Created and implemented Service Catalogs, workflows, Notifications for Client based on user requirement.

Creating Update Sets, Import Sets and Transform Maps to move customizations or between different environments of ServiceNow.

Involved in ServiceNow Upgrade from Kingston to London version and engaging ServiceNow vendor for fixes whenever

Done Cloning of PROD instance to sub production instances Worked on Automated Test Framework.

Knowledge on Service Portal configurations and HR Management.

Project #2: PAYPAL Managed Services Duration: March 2017 to May 2018

Tools: ServiceNow

Roles and Responsibilities:

Developed and Implemented Service Catalog items, Order guides, record producer, Variable Sets, UI Policies, Data policies, UI Actions, ACL's, Client Scripts, Business Rules and transform maps

Good working experience on handling Incident Management and Change Management.

Onsite - offshore communication and co-ordination.

Done Integration to insert the incidents created in SNOW populated to external tool.

Experience working with email notifications, reports, gauges, and homepages.

Worked on schedule jobs to automate the required tasks.

Created and maintained technical documentation and process map on components bug fixes.

Gave a knowledge session to the client and the team members about the functionality.

Knowledge on designing workflows as per the requirements.

Update set capturing and moving customizations to different instances.

Project #3: City of Long Beach Service Development

Duration: Nov 2016 to Feb 2017

Tools: ServiceNow

Roles and Responsibilities:

Users, Groups & Roles Administration. Merging the roles into other roles, maintaining the instance so that all the applications are available to respective users. Assigning Roles to Users.

Created UI Policies to make few fields visible, mandatory and vice versa based upon conditions

Written business rules to trigger the email events which send emails to users who have impacted and for whom that ticket

Written Client scripts for display and hide of some fields based on some conditions, to generate alerts for users help. Restricting the users who try to enter into table or form for which they don't have access. I am expert in analyzing which page will use by which role & how to restrict the users who enters into the tables through various cheat codes. Creation of catalog items with appropriate variables and variable sets and Catalog Client scripts.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
HTML, CSS		
JavaScript		
ServiceNow		3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SOAP and REST		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Beginner			
Telugu	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

1/21/2021 $https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=22cefb03ebb8af18417780142114c64d5b0958544a150d425140440959\dots\\$

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time